<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ezhik.jp</title>
        <link>https://ezhik.jp</link>
        <description>A website for an Internet Hedgehog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:06:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>ezhik.jp</generator>
        <copyright>© 2025 Ezhik</copyright>
        <atom:link href="https:/ezhik.jp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TIL]]></title>
            <link>/til</link>
            <guid>f1bb8b9dbef1c5349d6f9519a499d39022fc1dbf35a2e5ab0f99b459e65acdb1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 9999 00:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/the-more-you-know.gif" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/the-more-you-know.gif" alt="The More You Know">
										</a>
										<figcaption>The More You Know</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://ezhik.jp/assets/the-more-you-know.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hypertext Maximalism]]></title>
            <link>/hypertext-maximalism</link>
            <guid>7f7f9dc8053afdd5782967fc51ba842bd91c1df72156ec01b6694f1c13ec9a79</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I've always been enamored with the idea of note-taking but always struggled with actually practicing it. But I managed to develop a nice system for it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've always been enamored with the <em>idea</em> of note-taking but always struggled with actually practicing it. But I managed to develop a nice system for it.</p>
<p>And here it is:</p>
<h1>The System</h1>
<ol>
<li>Get a note-taking app with links and backlinks, such as <a href="/obsidian">Obsidian</a>.</li>
<li>Make sure every note is connected via links or backlinks to at least two other notes</li>
<li>Go write.</li>
</ol>
<h1>What?</h1>
<p>Okay, so. I've sucked at note-taking for most of my life.</p>
<p>Andy Mauschak's working notes. Zettelkasten. Johnny Decimal. Digital gardens. Bullet Journals. All these cool people and cool systems. I've tried to emulate them and I failed.</p>
<p>From piles of Moleskine notebooks to Surfaces and iPad Pros, from Evernote and OneNote to plain old text files and Apple Notes, there is a graveyard of note-taking tech in my drawers, including some attempts of my own like <a href="/notegram">Notegram</a> and <a href="/iroiro">IroIro</a> <s>and all the hours wasted trying to comprehend <code>contenteditable</code></s>. I was always looking for a better bicycle for the mind having never learned to ride a bike to begin with.</p>
<aside class="right">People who use some of the smarter systems I've mentioned above might instantly point out many flaws with hypertext maximalism, especially as the amount of notes grows. But consider this as a metaphorical <strong>ladder to be thrown away</strong>. This system got me to actually start note-taking consistently, and that I think is the most important aspect of it.</aside>
<p>I couldn't do analog notes because I'd misplace notebooks.<br>
I couldn't do folders because I'd always want to put one note into multiple folders.<br>
I couldn't do tags because I'd want to write a note about the tag itself.<br>
And so on, and so on, forever distracted by the meta-problem of <em>how</em> to write rather than <em>what</em> to write.</p>
<p>But one day a friend suggested Obsidian, and it just clicked for me – just the right kind of mix between Markdown and What-You-See-Is-What-You-Get, and, of course, the way it displays backlinks very, very prominently.</p>
<p>So I decided to just roll with it. Sick to death of worrying about these systems, I decided to just roll with the three rules above. No tags, no folders, no categories, no inboxes. Only hypertext. It's hypertext maximalism.</p>
<p>From zero notes three years ago, to 6,961 as of me writing this, I think this system worked out pretty well for me.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Posting a little more code]]></title>
            <link>/posting-a-little-more-code</link>
            <guid>4cad40ea6e7a218d5a18fe0e19243e514364e0c973c91a4d9d48be7e30910476</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Here's a little enhancement to the website. All the little apps will now have a little link to the source code on the bottom that'll take you to the website repository.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/hedgehog-footer.png" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/hedgehog-footer.jpg" alt="Posts with apps will now have a little &quot;source code&quot; link at the bottom.">
										</a>
										<figcaption>Posts with apps will now have a little &quot;source code&quot; link at the bottom.</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Here's a little enhancement to the website. All the little apps will now have a little link to the source code on the bottom that'll take you to the website repository.</p>
<aside class="right">Once again I was inspired by a TodePond talk - "<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MJzV0CX0q8o" class="external">What it means to be open</a>" this time.</aside>
<p>I'm now also including the original TypeScript code for these along with source maps, so if anybody here likes to play with browser developer tools, you'll hopefully have a better time doing it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://ezhik.jp/assets/thumbnails/hedgehog-footer.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spreadsheet #2]]></title>
            <link>/spreadsheet-2</link>
            <guid>b4d3cac3340999bfc86dcfc98007460086d375650ca359b1985a6e99e831ab0f</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What if we could set other properties besides just the cell value?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What if we could set other properties besides just the cell value?</p>
<p>Here's <a href="/spreadsheet-1">Spreadsheet No. 1</a> enhanced to allow setting properties based on other cells. It's still all nice and reactive.</p>
<p>I might be on to something interesting here...</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spreadsheet #1]]></title>
            <link>/spreadsheet-1</link>
            <guid>815167e9bda3680814b443e037967b535ea545651f965ede7a94f157996a671b</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Let's make a spreadsheet. No looking at hints or cool algorithms. All bugs are intentional.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let's make a spreadsheet. No looking at hints or cool algorithms. All bugs are intentional.</p>
<aside class="right"><p>Maybe we can call that <em>naive coding</em> – I just start writing and see where that takes me. Not sure how often people write spreadsheet software for fun, though.</p><p>And yes, I know that <code>eval</code> and friends are not production-grade.</p></aside>
<p>So, there's a very basic spreadsheet up above. In each cell, you can type a JavaScript expression and it will execute. You can refer to cells by the name that shows up when you hover your mouse cursor over a cell (<code>A1</code>, <code>B1</code>, <code>A2</code>, <code>B2</code>...).</p>
<h1>So how do you make a spreadsheet, anyway?</h1>
<p>I made a weird React hook that will give you:</p>
<ul>
<li>An object mapping cell IDs to formulas (just good old JS)</li>
<li>An object mapping cell IDs to computed values</li>
<li>A function to set a cell's value</li>
</ul>
<p>That hook also has an effect that actually handles cell recalculation. When a formula changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make a cache that'll store computed outputs</li>
<li>Convert all formulas to <code>AsyncFunction</code>s
<ul>
<li>Replace each cell reference with a retrieval of its cached result or queuing that cell reference's formula for execution and awaiting that execution's completion</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Execute all the <code>AsyncFunction</code>s and await for them to finish</li>
</ul>
<p>Spreadsheets are directed graphs and this is just recursive depth-first graph traversal in disguise, I suppose. I honestly thought this part would be harder, but it actually was alright. I think there are better ways to do it than using JavaScript promises as a weird cache, though.</p>
<h1>Some food for thought</h1>
<ul>
<li>Can the computation/caching be done using React somehow, rather than JS?</li>
<li>The whole spreadsheet gets redrawn on every change which is lame
<ul>
<li>That makes sense given that there is one big blob of all the data that's created at the spreadsheet level rather than at the cell level</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Cycles produce <code>NaN</code> – would love to step through that with a debugger to figure out why
<ul>
<li>Cool that they don't just freeze up or whatever, though</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Do cells really have to just be cells?</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The new domain]]></title>
            <link>/the-new-domain</link>
            <guid>b487ca3bab074dc08819f59c82991a9af9eb5826b0de288896ce16aeb3f073b4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On one of those good old days, I wanted to create an identity for myself online. I called myself Ezhik – a hedgehog – and I was building a corner on the internet that was for me. Hence, ezhik.me.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/2013-12-27-hog.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/2013-12-27-hog.jpg" alt="Hedgehogs and URLs during a trip a long time ago">
										</a>
										<figcaption>Hedgehogs and URLs during a trip a long time ago</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>On one of those <em>good old days</em>, I wanted to create an identity for myself online. I called myself <em>Ezhik</em> – a hedgehog – and I was building a corner on the internet that was for <em>me</em>. Hence, <em>ezhik.me</em>.</p>
<p>It was a different time. The internet was still young and there was still hope for a brighter future unburdened by all the baggage of history, all the war, all the nations, all the ideologies. The twentieth century was over but the twenty-first did not yet truly begin.</p>
<aside class="right">Young Ezhik was a naive idealist, I know.</aside>
<p>But times have changed. History never ended. And so we are back to the same old mess. <em>Cyberspace</em> never became independent. Worse than that, it was colonized. Little communities, all swept away by waves of corporate interests, propaganda, and psyops.</p>
<p>And so, rather than a cute domain hack, I have to look at <em>.me</em> for what it truly is: the top-level domain (TLD) for the country of Montenegro. And if I'm going to use a country-based TLD, rather than one that just so happened to have a nice ISO 3166 code, I might as well use the TLD for the country that accepted me.</p>
<p>So, <em>ezhik.jp</em> it is.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://ezhik.jp/assets/thumbnails/2013-12-27-hog.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Picture in Picture for your photo gallery]]></title>
            <link>/pip-pwa</link>
            <guid>064ec51176409c7000bf4445c9e7f0d3b2c1890cb24c102eae75b783bd1e9039</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My phone doesn't let me do picture in picture from its photo gallery and that's just stupid.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My phone doesn't let me do picture in picture from its photo gallery and that's just stupid.</p>
<p>So this little app will have to do instead.</p>
<p>Select a video by clicking that button above, it'll appear right below it. You can then PiP that.</p>
<p>I don't receive your videos, I don't need them. This is all like 50 lines of JavaScript magic.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixing 縦書き text in EPUBs on Kindle for iOS]]></title>
            <link>/fixing-縦書き-text-in-epubs-on-kindle-for-ios</link>
            <guid>82eb31e51ff8f261901779352ca62efbd9f360e64e4b8eea4893a944e16c786c</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I was uploading a Japanese book in .epub format via Send to Kindle, but ran into a weird issue: the book would not display as right-to-left vertical text (縦書き), instead displaying as horizontal, left-to-right text, on the Kindle app for iOS and Mac, while still looking fine on my Kindle e-reader.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was uploading a Japanese book in <code>.epub</code> format via <em>Send to Kindle</em>, but ran into a weird issue: the book would not display as right-to-left vertical text (縦書き), instead displaying as horizontal, left-to-right text, on the Kindle app for iOS and Mac, while still looking fine on my Kindle e-reader.</p>
<p><a href="https://note.com/atsu1166/n/nc2d0ad0f3aab" class="external">This note.com post by Atsu1166</a> has a fix that worked for me - edit the <code>.epub</code> file's <code>.opf</code> <em>rootfile</em> (This was <code>content.opf</code> in my case) to add the following tag in its <code>&#x3C;metadata></code>:</p>
<pre><code class="hljs language-xml"><span class="tag">&#x3C;<span class="name">meta</span> <span class="attr">name</span>=<span class="string">"primary-writing-mode"</span> <span class="attr">content</span>=<span class="string">"horizontal-rl"</span>/></span>
</code></pre>
<aside class="right">You read that right, <strong>horizontal</strong> and not <strong>vertical</strong>.</aside>
<p>For a bit more context, <code>.epub</code> files are really <code>.zip</code> archives containing all the files the book is made out of. You should be able to either unzip the file and edit that <code>.opf</code> <em>rootfile</em> manually, or, if you use Calibre, edit the epub to update it.</p>
<p>So far I only encountered <code>.opf</code> <em>rootfiles</em> located at the top of the archive, but apparently the EPUB standard specifies that these will be defined in the <code>META-INF/container.xml</code> file in a <code>&#x3C;rootfile></code> tag.</p>
<p><a href="/til">The more you know...</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adding a little interactivity]]></title>
            <link>/adding-a-little-interactivity</link>
            <guid>eb107c9093d88b0a70ad1b71d2e93ee6ed12f14ebb0ac655124fdb9f2e3a961b</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[There's this architecture called islands of interactivity – where you add little interactive bits here and there on an otherwise static website. And that sure reminds me of Flash – you'd have a static website, but it'd have an an interactive SWF file embedded, which would include fun stuff.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There's this architecture called <em>islands of interactivity</em> – where you add little interactive bits here and there on an otherwise static website. And that sure reminds me of Flash – you'd have a static website, but it'd have an an interactive SWF file embedded, which would include fun stuff.</p>
<p>I like that approach. The website still works just fine if you don't have JavaScript, but at the same time you can bring in fun bits of interactivity. Make little apps and stuff. So I tried building this for my website too, and the little <a href="/react">React</a> hello world is a demonstration of that.</p>
<p>These days, <a href="https://react.dev" class="external">react.dev</a> tries really hard to force you to use stuff like Next.js and whatnot. But if you try, you can figure out how to build some little toy web apps that don't require you to get weird with web servers. Just write some code and just make yourself a little app that'll sit in its own rectangle. It's not a big deal. It's not the next big startup. It's just there for you and whoever else you share it with.</p>
<p>I really do miss Flash.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fxtec Pro1 X: The silliest battery fix]]></title>
            <link>/fxtec-pro1-x-the-silliest-battery-fix</link>
            <guid>dbdcfc6bd19a9c9aa2a0954185af418fdf4d0b0f912955e9fb01d13972c388b5</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 14:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My Fxtec Pro1 X died a very silly death. It lost so much battery it wouldn't charge anymore. The phone sat dead in my drawer until I came across a very silly fix.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/fxtec-pro1-x-battery-trick.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/fxtec-pro1-x-battery-trick.jpg" alt="A Fxtec Pro1 X, reviving very slowly">
										</a>
										<figcaption>A Fxtec Pro1 X, reviving very slowly</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>My <a href="/fxtec-pro1-x">Fxtec Pro1 X</a> died a very silly death. It lost so much battery it wouldn't charge anymore. The phone sat dead in my drawer until I came across <a href="https://community.fxtec.com/topic/4106-a-user-found-a-way-to-charge-a-dead-pro1x-confirmed-by-others/" class="external">a very silly fix</a>.</p>
<p>When you hold the power button for like 10 seconds, it'll draw <em>juuust</em> a little bit of power. So if you leave it in that state overnight, it will charge like 6%, which is enough for it to revive and start changing normally.</p>
<p><a href="/til">The more you know!</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://ezhik.jp/assets/thumbnails/fxtec-pro1-x-battery-trick.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The new website: Day 2]]></title>
            <link>/the-new-website-day-2</link>
            <guid>42a1806a85928c4364af9544e16d7c1626f715d8e1cb18eb12f72ce1302a7589</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Yesterday I launched the new website on a whim. All things considered, it's pretty cool. Of course, I caught some bugs that are now fixed (but there are plenty still left to feed a hedgehog, I'm sure.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I launched <a href="/the-new-website">the new website</a> on a whim. All things considered, it's pretty cool. Of course, I caught some bugs that are now fixed (but there are plenty still left to feed a hedgehog, I'm sure.</p>
<p>Here are some little things I fixed though:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reduced margins on smaller screens</li>
<li>Added image previews in <code>&#x3C;meta></code> tags</li>
<li>Made RSS descriptions nicer</li>
<li>Fixed the external link indicator on Safari</li>
<li>Made overflows look prettier</li>
<li>Made the hog resize less</li>
<li>Removed some weird stuff like old font imports</li>
<li>Kinda sorta integrated <a href="/radical-lookup">Radical Lookup</a> into this now (it's an <code>&#x3C;iframe></code> going to the old page, glitchhog aesthetics and all. Flash embed type vibes.)</li>
</ul>
<p>I also made a <a href="/til">TIL</a> page. Swap the backlinks and the articles and bam, it's now a tag. Neat. To make it even neater, I made a weird <code>~[[TIL]]</code> syntax that'll exclude that TIL link from its backlinks.</p>
<p>And since this is a blog about my hedgehog stuff, I'll try to post some stuff that's not just about this blog. Blogging about blogging and taking notes about taking notes. I hate getting stuck in metawork. So I made a small post about a gadget I was messing with: <a href="/fxtec-pro1-x-the-silliest-battery-fix">Fxtec Pro1 X - The silliest battery fix</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The new website]]></title>
            <link>/the-new-website</link>
            <guid>6c08f5dd70a1b546c9c9e49a0931b12546288829683b320bb62c05905af6dc0d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I wanted to make a new website for a while. I thought I'd be cool and do it right and stuff, but then I watched Lu Wilson's Death of the Tadiweb and decided to wing it because life is too short to bikeshed a homebrew blogging engine especially since this one is a horror show that uses SvelteKit for some reason even though the whole thing is just a static website with some islands of interactivity Flash applet-style. Don't ask. Or do. Do ask. Email me. i@ezhik.me. Let's chat. Send me stories. Send me your favorite hedgehog picture or story or video or song or app or novel. Send me small computers.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to make a new website for a while. I thought I'd be cool and do it right and stuff, but then I watched Lu Wilson's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=73mEhS0gxgI" class="external"><em>Death of the Tadiweb</em></a> and decided to wing it because life is too short to bikeshed a homebrew blogging engine especially since this one is a horror show that uses SvelteKit for some reason even though the whole thing is just a static website with some islands of interactivity Flash applet-style. Don't ask. Or do. Do ask. Email me. <a href="mailto:i@ezhik.me" class="external">i@ezhik.me</a>. Let's chat. Send me stories. Send me your favorite hedgehog picture or story or video or song or app or novel. Send me small computers.</p>
<p>So here we are. I'm still scouring the internet for my various blog posts (I recovered one so far and it's a silly one!). I've also moved most of my existing stuff on the old site over - ping me if anything's missing as I'm sure it's not gone forever and I want to put it all back.</p>
<p>Also... There's now an <a href="/feed.xml">✨RSS feed✨</a>. Please follow it.</p>
<p>I've also got ✨backlinks✨. It's all because of my <a href="https://obsidian.md" class="external">Obsidian</a> addiction. Who needs folders or tags when you have hypertext? Hypertext is all you need. Expect lots of hypertext.</p>
<p>Since it's been a while since I did web stuff and the internet became a very different place during that time, I also now have a <a href="/privacy-policy">Privacy Policy</a>.</p>
<p>Please enjoy.</p>
<p>P.S.<br>
What do you think of that hog? I was kinda winging it with this one and don't know if I like this hog or not.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Privacy Policy]]></title>
            <link>/privacy-policy</link>
            <guid>8f75388c2d6c62bb7f249cedf492e5f4413c8c020fb1b85a85ddc481244aa0f7</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 14:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I was too lazy to put spyware on this site so you'll have to share your personal information with me manually. You must email i@ezhik.me with your engagement metrics or wild hedgehogs will bite your ankles.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was too lazy to put spyware on this site so you'll have to share your personal information with me manually. You must email <a href="mailto:i@ezhik.me" class="external">i@ezhik.me</a> with your engagement metrics or wild hedgehogs will bite your ankles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The objectively correct guide to making Vim use the system clipboard]]></title>
            <link>/vim-clipboard</link>
            <guid>c467f8943446eab0441b6a56d200189714643d771b847f69c4637824bf560d75</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Make sure your Vim has clipboard support (run vim --version and check for +clipboard), stick this in your .vimrc or Neovim's init.vim, enjoy life:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Make sure your Vim has clipboard support (run <code>vim --version</code> and check for <code>+clipboard</code>), stick this in your <code>.vimrc</code> or Neovim's <code>init.vim</code>, enjoy life:</p>
<pre><code class="hljs language-vim"><span class="keyword">set</span> clipboard=
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">y</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">y</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="string">""</span>yy <span class="string">""</span>yy
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">p</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">p</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">P</span> <span class="string">""</span><span class="keyword">P</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="symbol">&#x3C;expr></span> <span class="keyword">y</span>  (<span class="variable">v:register</span> ==# <span class="string">'"'</span> ? <span class="string">'"+'</span> : <span class="string">''</span>) . <span class="string">'y'</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="symbol">&#x3C;expr></span> yy (<span class="variable">v:register</span> ==# <span class="string">'"'</span> ? <span class="string">'"+'</span> : <span class="string">''</span>) . <span class="string">'yy'</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="symbol">&#x3C;expr></span> <span class="keyword">p</span>  (<span class="variable">v:register</span> ==# <span class="string">'"'</span> ? <span class="string">'"+'</span> : <span class="string">''</span>) . <span class="string">'p'</span>
<span class="keyword">noremap</span> <span class="symbol">&#x3C;expr></span> <span class="keyword">P</span>  (<span class="variable">v:register</span> ==# <span class="string">'"'</span> ? <span class="string">'"+'</span> : <span class="string">''</span>) . <span class="string">'P'</span>
</code></pre>
<p>That's it, post over, go home.</p>
<h2>Wait, what?</h2>
<p>Okay, so. Vi was originally invented in 1300 BC, before we had GUIs and even the idea of a shared system clipboard. What it had (and what Vim still has today) instead were registers. Registers are basically a bunch of internal Vim clipboards that you can use through the <code>"</code> key — for example, <code>"fy</code> to copy something into the <code>f</code> register, then <code>"fp</code> to paste from it.</p>
<p>By default, anything you yank (Vim's word for copy) goes into the unnamed register (which is actually assigned to the <code>"</code> key, so you can yank something into it explicitly by doing <code>""y</code>. Then, what Vim's standard way of handling the system clipboard does is simply link up this unnamed register to your global clipboard. Nice and cool, until you overwrite everything you copied with a single character that you just deleted.</p>
<p>See, anything you delete using keys such as <code>x</code>, <code>d</code>, <code>c</code>, and the like, also goes into this unnamed register, overwriting it (<code>"fd</code> would delete something into the <code>f</code> register, by the way). This may have been okay if you were back in Heian Era Japan and all you had was a simple VT100 terminal to write love poems on, as you would have been living inside Vi anyway, using its registers extensively. However, in this day and age, you want to be consistent with the modern OS you're running Vim on (and if you aren't on a modern OS, the Vim on the ancient computer you're configuring is compiled without clipboard support anyway).</p>
<p>Anyone first starting to learn Vim will absolutely not be expecting their clipboard to be wiped every time they delete something, and it will drive them <em>insane</em>. They'll look around the internet for a solution, and they will only find two things.</p>
<p>The first is a bunch of ideology from Unix purists about how you're supposed to just live with that, get used to the Vim way, that poetry declined under the Kamakura shogunate, et cetera. Those people are important and help prevent this world from going completely off the rails drunk on overhyped technology, but listening to them for too long will quickly make the newcomer to Vim start to hate life. To any Vim newcomers reading this, now is also a good time to mention that if you want to have tabs in Vim, search for how to use Vim's buffers. Vim has another feature called tabs, but those are not actually tabs at all. It's complicated and everyone online will be telling you about the Vim way even though you just want to have a little bar on top with two text files that you can quickly switch between.</p>
<p>But anyway. Any newcomer not scared off at this point will keep looking and will find a bunch of solutions that remap the various delete commands to use the "void" (<code>_</code>) register. Those are <em>okay</em>, until you actually do want to use registers the Vim way, plus you'll have to play whack-a-mole with every single command that puts text in the clipboard register.</p>
<p>So what you really want is to just remap the yank (copy) and paste keys to use the system clipboard register. That's exactly what that snippet of code does.</p>
<p>The first line disables any sort of clipboard integration that may have been enabled by default (along with selections automatically getting yanked — change that to <code>set clipboard=autoselect</code> if you're really into that sort of thing and if your Vim supports it).</p>
<p>The last four lines change the main yank and paste keys: if you invoke a yank or paste command with the default unnamed register, it swaps that register out for the system clipboard one instead.</p>
<p>The four lines above those add an exception to the rule: if you explicitly try to use the unnamed register, it will be used instead. Make sure you get the order of the lines right in your Vim configuration file, or who knows what might happen.</p>
<p>So, with the clipboard set up this way, everybody wins! You get to have sane clipboard settings that work the same way as the rest of your OS, while still having the flexibility of proper registers if you need it.</p>
<p>The end!</p>
<p>P.S. If you find out that I made a mistake in my hubris, please email me at <a href="mailto:i@ezhik.jp" class="external">i@ezhik.jp</a>, or maybe make an issue on this site's <a href="https://github.com/SilverEzhik/ezhik.jp/issues" class="external">GitHub</a> if it's urgent enough to require public shaming. Thanks!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Radical Lookup]]></title>
            <link>/radical-lookup</link>
            <guid>ee27ecbd383367d36623d80a3efde2a38058545e7f2912c2a97b002f6900b075</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This is a kanji radical lookup tool with a little twist - it allows you to also decompose a kanji with its radicals. This is useful if you remember a kanji that uses a certain radical, but are not sure how many strokes it actually has (which you'd need to know to use the Jisho radical tool, for example).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<aside class="right">I haven't gotten around to rebuilding this one for the new site yet so enjoy it in all of its glitchhog aesthetic glory. That's an <code>&#x3C;iframe></code> right there.</aside>
<p>This is a kanji radical lookup tool with a little twist - it allows you to also decompose a kanji with its radicals. This is useful if you remember a kanji that uses a certain radical, but are not sure how many strokes it actually has (which you'd need to know to use the Jisho radical tool, for example).</p>
<p>This uses <a href="http://www.edrdg.org/krad/kradinf.html" class="external">KRADFILE</a> for looking things up.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/SilverEzhik/radical-lookup" class="external">Source (GPL3)</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond 184]]></title>
            <link>/beyond184</link>
            <guid>e350b3cb6779c7538d47c82cc2d85495f6a6f9f616c208f75d63cfe0611b3f63</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Beyond 184 is a cellular automata for simulating traffic in an urban setting.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Beyond 184</strong> is a cellular automata for simulating traffic in an urban setting.</p>
<p>Every single one of those little cars is not just going in a straight line, but is instead behaving similarly to an actual car – accelerating as they move through an empty road, and slowing down before obstacles.</p>
<p>It is based on the Rule 184 CA (hence the name), with enhancements made to add varying speed levels and to make the whole thing work in two dimensions.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/SilverEzhik/beyond184" class="external">Source (GPL2)</a>  <a href="/assets/old/beyond184/conference.pdf">Paper</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Things I learned when I decided to put every single sticker I could find in my room on my laptop]]></title>
            <link>/laptop-stickers</link>
            <guid>7a7ee980c06a3aa9627d869098020cbce1f415d8ea8599af12dc6d7056b79832</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 18:34:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[After a hackathon, you are always left with a lot of swag.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/1.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/1.jpg" alt="please help">
										</a>
										<figcaption>please help</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>After a hackathon, you are always left with a lot of swag.</p>
<p>Shirts, bags, and, of course <em>stickers</em>.</p>
<p><em>So many stickers.</em></p>
<p>So of course, the most logical thing to do, is to put them all to use.</p>
<p>All of them.</p>
<p>Here are the lessons I have learned when torturing my poor laptop with all these stickers.</p>
<h2>Google stickers have strong adhesive.</h2>
<p>Like, good luck getting those guys off. There’s an upside down SQL sticker somewhere in that mess and it’s never going to get fixed.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/2.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/2.jpg" alt="why are you doing this">
										</a>
										<figcaption>why are you doing this</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<h4>I’m pretty sure some of these aren’t even hackathon stickers.</h4>
<p>Where did I even get these?</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/3.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/3.jpg" alt="these don’t even look good">
										</a>
										<figcaption>these don’t even look good</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<h4>Big red stickers are boring.</h4>
<p>Come on man, don’t monopolize my laptop lid.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/4.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/4.jpg" alt="didn’t you plan to put mac os on me">
										</a>
										<figcaption>didn’t you plan to put mac os on me</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<h4>“Transparent” stickers are the coolest.</h4>
<p>Check them out, they’re really neat.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/5.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/5.jpg" alt="you can’t even read what the sticker says">
										</a>
										<figcaption>you can’t even read what the sticker says</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<h4>I have a lot of HackingEDU stickers.</h4>
<p>Too many, in fact.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/6.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/6.jpg" alt="stop">
										</a>
										<figcaption>stop</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Seriously.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/7.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/7.jpg" alt="at least don’t wrinkle them dude">
										</a>
										<figcaption>at least don’t wrinkle them dude</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Where did I even get so many?</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/8.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/8.jpg" alt="bad">
										</a>
										<figcaption>bad</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>I hope I didn’t take all the stickers or something. Stickers are meant for sharing.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/9.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/9.jpg" alt="i am a thinkpad i don’t need these stickers">
										</a>
										<figcaption>i am a thinkpad i don’t need these stickers</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Still, so many stickers.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/10.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/10.jpg" alt="at least put another “ship it” one">
										</a>
										<figcaption>at least put another “ship it” one</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Like, damn.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/11.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/11.jpg" alt=":(">
										</a>
										<figcaption>:(</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<h4>Conclusion</h4>
<p>I had a big pile of stickers, and now I don’t. Please look forward to the next installment when I try to peel all of these off.</p>
<p>
									<figure>
										<a href="/assets/laptop-stickers/12.jpg" target="_blank">
											<img src="/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/12.jpg" alt="The dark side of Sticker Culture">
										</a>
										<figcaption>The dark side of Sticker Culture</figcaption>
									</figure>
								</p>
<p>Also, shout-outs to HHCdT and <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150801122117/http://hackingedu.co/" class="external">HackingEDU</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://ezhik.jp/assets/thumbnails/laptop-stickers/1.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeroPlan]]></title>
            <link>/zeroplan</link>
            <guid>d2f3375f470771a07de3da15f0bfe830bd6c86610bd2708267c3093223508e41</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ZeroPlan is a simple app that switches the power plan from “High Performance” to “Power Saver” when you unplug your PC, and vice versa.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>ZeroPlan</strong> is a simple app that switches the power plan from “High Performance” to “Power Saver” when you unplug your PC, and vice versa.</p>
<p>It has no installer, no GUI, no options, and uses only a little more than 1 MB of your RAM. Just stick it in your Autorun folder, and you’re ready to go.</p>
<p>It uses Net Framework 4.5, so in theory it should be able to run on jailbroken Windows RT devices.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mediafire.com/download/r4749ke5wkh7kpx/ZeroPlan.zip" class="external">Download</a>  <a href="https://github.com/SilverEzhik/ZeroPlan" class="external">Source (GPL2)</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>